Adam Pohl

5 The Meadows, Marshfield, Cardiff, CF3 2AY e-mail: adam.pohl9999@gmail.com

Tel: (+44) 1633 681190 Mob: (+44) 7936 363296

Date of Birth: 23^{rd} December 1993

Nationality: British (Welsh)

INTRODUCTION

A final year Mathematics undergraduate at Cardiff University, with a strong interest in computer programming. An instrumental member of the schools code club, with experience of handling various managerial duties, web development and encouraging new learners.

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS

Cardiff University 2013 – present

BSc Mathematics, Operational Research and Statistics Modules include: Accountancy, Modelling with differential equations, Computational Statistics, Visual basic programing for OR, Analysis,

Rougemont School, Newport

2011 - 2013

4 A Levels: Maths (A*), Further Maths (B), Chemistry (B), Physics (B). UCAS points: 440

St Davids Sixth Form College, Cardiff

Computing for Maths (Python and Sagemath).

2010 - 2011

A Levels: Maths, Further Maths, Chemistry, Physics, Young Engineers.

Rougemont School, Newport

2003 - 2010

9 GCSEs: Maths (A*), Physics (A*), Statistics (A), Chemistry (A), English Literature (A), Biology (B), English Language (B), Geography (B), History (B), OCR Level 2 Key Skills in ICT.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Computing for Maths tutorials

Oct 2014 - Dec 2014, Oct 2015 - Dec 2015

• After a strong performance in this course, the module leader specifically chose me to act as a tutor. This involved the teaching of Python and Sagemath to subsequent first year students.

TK Maxx, Newport.

Oct 2010 - present

- Part time Store Associate
- Financial transactions and customer relations.

Silvertel, Newport. Aug 2010

- Electronic component testing, programming of parts.
- Edited web pages using Adobe Dreamweaver, mechanical assembly.
- Completed a stock check using SAGE, circuit drawing on Visio.

• Certified ECB level 1 cricket coach.

RELEVENT SKILLS

• IT/Computer Programming

In completing the Computing for Mathematics module, I have learnt how to code in python and also how to write mathematics in IATEX. I found this to be very enjoyable and as computers are an essential part of any business, I feel that being able to code is a valuable skill to have.

Last year I undertook the Introduction to Computational Statistics module in which I learnt how to code in R and use it as a software environment to do statistical computing/analysis.

Within the last year I have become a contributor to various open source software projects used by the international programming community: git-control and script (for use with the Atom editor). I contribute to these projects through modern software development tools and practices including git and github.

Over the last two years I have been involved in the setting up and running of a code club in the Maths department at my university. This has helped me to improve my web development skills through the creation and maintenance of the clubs' website.

• Communication, Presentation and Interpersonal skills

The communication and interpersonal skills are evidenced through my work in retail (TK Maxx): I regularly give first class service to customers.

During code club We have often have lighting talks, in which we have to go up to the front and present something code related to the rest of the group. This has helped me with my presentation and communication skills as I have to make sure that (a) what I am talking about is easy enough for others to understand and (b) I am ready for any potential questions that may be come about from my presentation.

• Analytical and Problem solving

As a mathematics graduate I have developed these skill fully through my modules. Furthermore my high level of programming experience further evidences my analytical and problem solving abilities.

• Team work

One of the pieces of coursework in Computing for Maths was that we had to do a group project. This experience has shown me that in order for any team to be successful, you must develop effective working relationships with all members of the group. It has also helped me to better understand the phrase: every idea is a useful idea, because it made me recognise generating innovative solutions can sometimes be more meaningful and useful than the final outcome itself. We were able to achieve a score of 86% by utilising our strengths to their best advantage.

• Leadership

When I did Young Engineers, I was the leader of my group and helped us to become the best team in Wales that year by only dropping two marks overall, the best team in the UK only dropped one mark, and win the award for best presentation. At TK Maxx I quite often have to run the tills and look after/teach the new people on the tills.

As a founding member of code club, I often have to run it when the residing lecturer is unavailable. This has involved me deciding what the focus of the code club will be and also arranging any lighting talks that would be taking place. Another way in which I have used code club to enhance my leadership skills is that, like with TK Maxx, I often have to guide/teach new members on how to contribute to the website and also where they may have gone wrong with regards to any code they are writing.

• Business and Commercial Awareness

Having worked in retail for the past four years, I feel that I have gained a good commercial awareness as I have had to make sure that whatever part of the store I was in, it was always neat and tidy as to make it more appealing to the customer. It has also given me a better business awareness as we have regular meetings about how the business is doing, be it my store or TJX Europe, and how what I do on the shop floor can help the business to grow.

INTERESTS AND ACHIVEMENTS

Cricket, Tennis, Golf, Reading,
Duke of Edinburgh Bronze award in 2009,
Lead Young Engineers group to being the best group in Wales.

REFEREES

Dr Nikos Savva, Personal tutor, School of Mathematics, Senghennydd Road, Cardiff, CF24 4AG Mr Ian Morgan, Cricket coach, 7 Sable Close, Lisvane, Cardiff, CF14 0GF